tattoodesign.com 2010-11-20

# Privacy Policy - TattooDesign.com

Date of Last Revision: January 8, 2009

| What information do we collect?  
---  
We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey or fill out a form. 

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number or credit card information. You may, however, visit our site anonymously. 

Like most websites, we use cookies and/or web beacons to enhance your experience, gather general visitor information, and track visits to our website. Please refer to the 'do we use cookies?' section below for information about cookies and how we use them.   
  
What do we use your information for?  
---  
Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways: 

1\. To personalize your experience  
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs) 

2\. To improve our website  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you) 

3\. To improve customer service  
(your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs) 

4\. To process transactions  
Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested. 

5\. To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature

6\. To send periodic emails  
The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order, in addition to receiving occasional company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. 

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.   
  
How do we protect your information?  
---  
We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order. 

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. 

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.   
  
Do we use cookies?  
---  
Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information 

We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart, understand and save your preferences for future visits, and keep track of advertisements and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business. 

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers' respective websites.   
  
Do we disclose any information to outside parties?  
---  
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.   
Forums and Other Interactive Services  
---  
Our sites may include discussion forums or other interactive areas or services, including blogs, chat rooms, bulletin boards, message boards, online hosting or storage services, or other areas or services in which you or third parties create, post or store any content, messages, comments, materials or other items on the sites ("Interactive Areas"). If you use an Interactive Area, you should be aware that these areas are open to the public and any personal information you post or provide at registration may be viewable by others. We are not responsible for personal information you submit in connection with the Interactive Areas, nor are we responsible for how others might use that information, including to send you unsolicited messages. Interactive Area postings may be retained indefinitely. Keep in mind that removal of a posting from an Interactive Area does not mean that the posting will be deleted from our systems.   
Email Referrals  
---  
If you choose to use our email referral services to tell a friend about our products or services, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will use that information to send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site and review the product or service you have selected. We may use a third-party provider to administer this function, but any such third-party provider may only use the information submitted to facilitate this one-time email.   
Third-Party Links  
---  
Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.   
Third-Party Advertisers and Web Beacons  
---  
Some of our advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to the advertisements and links that appear on TattooDesign send directly to your browsers. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or Web Beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements and/or to personalize the advertising content that you see. 

TattooDesign has no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. 

You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. TattooDesign's privacy policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or web sites. 

In particular, you should know the following: Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on TattooDesign. Google's use of the [DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx) enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).   
  
California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance  
---  
Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.   
Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance  
---  
We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.   
Online Privacy Policy Only  
---  
This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.   
Terms and Conditions  
---  
Please also visit our [Terms and Conditions](http://www.tattoodesign.com/terms_and_conditions/) section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our website.   
Your Consent  
---  
By using our site, you consent to our privacy policy.   
Changes to our Privacy Policy  
---  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.   
Contacting Us  
---  
If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below. 

2442 Cerrillos Rd. #146  
Santa Fe, NM 87505  
United States
